EDWIN AMPONSAH

+(233)501430183 | edwinamponsah@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwin-amponsah-a161a25a

Stallion Consultants Limited, Ghana

A near-ASA candidate with experience in Employment benefits Valuation, Life and Non-Life Insurance Business actuarial methods and practices. Possesses strong problem solving and analytical skills and enjoys solving challenging problems that bring impact to society.

EDUCATION

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology (KNUST)

Kumasi, Ghana

• BSc. Actuarial Science (Honors), CWA: 85.82/100

Sept 2015 - June 2019

Graduating Thesis: Actuarial Multistate Modelling of Insurance Claims Payment Process

ACTUARIAL EXAMINATIONS

Passed: Exam P, Exam FM, Exam IFM, Exam STAM, EXAM LTAM, Exam SRM (Waiver)

VEEs obtained: Applied Statistics, Corporate Finance, Economics

WORK EXPERIENCE

Actuarial Analyst, Stallion Consultants Limited

August 2020 - Present

- Conducted actuarial valuations of employee benefit schemes under IAS 19 for corporate entities.
- Developed actuarial valuation models for valuing new employee benefit schemes.
- Execution of annual actuarial reserving of Technical Liabilities/Life Fund Reserve under IFRS 4.
- Assisted in the preparation of Financial Conditional Report (FCR) for insurance companies.

Teaching and Research Assistant, Dept. of Statistics & Actuarial Sci., KNUST August 2019 – August 2020

- Organized tutorial and graded assignments in Probability, Calculus and Mathematics for Physics
- Created technology-based learning materials and instructional materials using Moodle
- Guided undergraduate students in analyzing data for their project

Relationship Officer Intern, Unibank Ghana Ltd (now CBG)

June 2016 - July 2016

- Assessed and evaluated credit risk in loan applications
- Assisted in preparation and submission of daily and weekly report to Management.

HONORS AND AWARDS

•	Vice-Chancellor's Award for Overall Best Graduating Student	July, 2019
•	Prudential Actuarial Support System for Excellence in Actuarial Science Award	July,2019
•	MasterCard Foundation Scholarship	August 2015 - July 2019

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AND EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

President, KNUST Actuarial Club

August 2015 - August 2020

- Organized tutorial sessions and mentored students to pass actuarial exams P and FM
- Liaised with lecturers, alumnus, and student body to establish a fund for the actuarial club

Founder, Happy Faces I.T Program

August 2017 – Sept. 2019

• Trained about 30 children from Senya Beraku on basic I.T skills

Participant, Scholars Baobab Summit-Kigali, Rwanda

July 2019

• Pitched an I.T training project for the deaf as a Semi-Finalist at the Social Venture Challenge

Project and Innovations Coordinator, KNUST MasterCard Scholars' Council

Dec 2016 - May 2018

- Secured funds and successfully organized a blood donation project on KNUST campus
- Assisted Mastercard scholars to develop proposals for their individual community projects

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Proficient in Microsoft Excel, VBA, MATLAB, R, LaTeX
- Coursework in Octave through completing Machine Learning course on Coursera